<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Shoble Tech Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>A modern digital technology blog to keep you up to date with the tech world.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:31:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Apple iPhone 14 Release</title>
		<link>/2022/10/05/apple-iphone-14-release/</link>
					<comments>/2022/10/05/apple-iphone-14-release/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oscar Zhou]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 21:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A magical new way to interact with iPhone. Groundbreaking safety features designed to save lives. An innovative 48MP camera for mind-blowing detail. All powered by the ultimate smartphone chip. Many people would argue that the most significant change is the dynamic island. This feature combines the power of the iPhone itself and the power of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><gwmw style="display:none;"><gwmw style="display:none;"><gwmw style="display:none;"></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1024" height="438" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Screenshot-2022-10-06-at-8.19.15-am-1024x438.png" alt="" class="wp-image-10" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Screenshot-2022-10-06-at-8.19.15-am-1024x438.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Screenshot-2022-10-06-at-8.19.15-am-300x128.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Screenshot-2022-10-06-at-8.19.15-am-768x329.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Screenshot-2022-10-06-at-8.19.15-am-1536x657.png 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Screenshot-2022-10-06-at-8.19.15-am-2048x877.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>The iPhone 14 Pro</figcaption></figure>



<p>A magical new way to interact with iPhone. Groundbreaking safety features designed to save lives. An innovative 48MP camera for mind-blowing detail. All powered by the ultimate smartphone chip.</p>



<p>Many people would argue that the most significant change is the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.apple.com/iphone-14-pro/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.apple.com/iphone-14-pro/" target="_blank">dynamic island</a>. This feature combines the power of the iPhone itself and the power of iOS 16. The new home screen design brings a fresh and unique feeling to the iPhone. The dynamic island not only gives the user more screen, but it also has been turned into a seamless feature. Features such as FaceID take great advantage of it to provide a neat and fresh experience. The new animations that Apple has designed for the dynamic island may seem strange at first, but they effectively allow you to multitask and check out the progress of a timer without leaving the app you&#8217;re already in.</p>



<p>Another part of the dynamic island is the selfie camera. With social media platforms such as TikTok taking over the internet, the front selfie camera has never been more important. This year, Apple has decided to upgrade the front selfie camera &#8211; by a lot. Around 95% of the smartphone market focuses most of its camera budget on the rear cameras, but clearly, Apple has once again changed the game with their new advanced selfie camera. This is not to say that Apple has not improved on their rear camera.</p>



<p>Apple has also added a new safety feature to the iPhone. SOS via satellite. Because the signals that satellites can send and receive can get extremely weak, Apple has limited the satellite communication service to emergencies only. The only problem is that this is a subscription service. It will be free for the first two years, but not after that.</p>



<p>Apple has also decided to upgrade its display on the iPhone 14. The new display can go up to 2000 nits in outdoor situations. This is also the highest brightness ever recorded on a smartphone. Another feature is the always-on display in the new pro models. During the always-on display, the screen refresh rate can go all the way down to 1hz. This saves a lot of battery life!</p>



<p>Whilst most of the new features seem to be mostly in the pro models, Apple has scrapped the iPhone Mini lineup and has swapped it in for the iPhone 14 Plus. The iPhone 14 Plus has been promised to have a longer battery life compared to the iPhone 14 and a larger display. Whilst you can not buy the iPhone 14 Plus currently, people have been attracted to this concept. The iPhone 14 Plus will give you maybe 3-4 more hours of battery life without having to spring to a Pro model.</p>



<p>Apple has also upgraded the rear cameras. The rear cameras now have a slightly better sensor, which in turn means better stabilization and a faster shutter time. Apple has also introduced a new piece of software called the Photonic Engine which can bring in two times more light in night shots. Apple has also introduced &#8220;Action Mode.&#8221; Action mode is designed for sport and movement. It is basically a stabilizer that uses the more advanced built-in sensor. But, the biggest upgrade is the main camera, which is now capable of shooting 48 Megapixel photos. Compare that with last year&#8217;s 12MP camera!</p>



<p>Apple has also introduced a newer 5G signal receiver which is now capable of receiving at faster speeds. The problem is, the receiver has only been upgraded in the Pro models.</p>



<p>The main part of a phone is the chip. Last year, the A15 was so much faster than all the rest of the android chipsets. This year, it&#8217;s even faster. A phone&#8217;s chip is not just about the performance. The power efficiency, the machine learning, the graphics engine and the Artificial Intelligence levels all contribute to how people may rate the phone.</p>



<p>In conclusion, the iPhone 14 is a giant leap from last year&#8217;s iPhone 13. Every year, Apple keeps improving their products. But this year might have the greatest improvement to date.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2022/10/05/apple-iphone-14-release/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello world!</title>
		<link>/2022/10/05/hello-world/</link>
					<comments>/2022/10/05/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oscar Zhou]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 21:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2022/10/05/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
